

**p:** 678.451.7358

swhutchison(at)gmail.com

a: Marietta, GA 30062

w: house-of-wonder.com

I have worked on the web since 2001. I learned HTML as a content writer, that led to learning design, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, PHP, CSHTML, Mustache, Handlebars, Git, NPM...the list goes on and on. My favorite thing to work on is building reusable components and patterns in HTML, CSS and Javascript. Nowadays, it's HTML5, SASS, and ES6.

## **Skills**

I have dabbled in Angular and React, but I prefer vanilla JS or ES6 and functional programming patterns that can be tested easily. Components built this way can be used in Angular, React, or another framework. I use Compass and SASS to compile CSS, as well as libSASS and PostCSS/CSSNext. CSS and the presentation layer are where my skills are the strongest. I lead code reviews of our front end code and run a team of developers, some onshore and some offshore. I've collaborated across teams to deliver projects that all teams roll out. I have worked as a mentor and I've been pair programming for about a year. I've been following Agile development processes for several years, occasionally running hackathons.

I have strong opinions about how code should be written, mainly that there should be a separation of concerns, it should be modular, it should be easily testable and it should be composable. Presentation classes should follow BEM or other naming convention. Anything binded by Javascript should get a clearly identifiable class that will never have styles written on it. Avoid binding to raw HTML elements, instead use a class or ID prefixed with js-. Having said this, adhering to agreed upon standards and testing is the best way to ensure anti-patterns are not created.

Here are some of the skills I have developed and software I've used to develop web applications:

- HTML5/Mustache/Handlebars
- Javascript/ES6/Functional Programming/Jquery
- CSS/SASS/CSSNext/PostCSS/OOCSS/BEM
- GitHub/GitLab/Subversion(SVN)
- NPM/Artifactory
- RequireJS/AMD Modules
- Karma test runner
- Jasmine unit test framework
- Istanbul code coverage monitor
- Agile/Scrum/Pivotal/XP programming
- Paired Programming

- HomeBrew
- Visual Studio Code/Sublime Text
- NodeJS
- · Maven/Tomcat
- Eclipse
- SVG
- Sketch
- · Custom Font icons
- Developing for Touch Devices
- Responsive Design/Layout
- FlexBox Master



**p:** 678.451.7358

e:

swhutchison(at)gmail.com

a: Marietta, GA 30062

house-of-wonder.com

# **Experience**

## The Home Depot // 2013 to present

I am a Senior Software Engineer for The Home Depot currently transitioning to a lead position. When I joined in 2013, it was as a developer on the Mobile Web team. We built the Mobile website and the tablet website. I have a deep understanding of touch based websites. Later, I worked on building the responsive framework we use for both tablet and desktop. In all of these roles, I've led developers and worked closely with UX designers and business partners to build out and devliver the best experience for our customers. This resulted in a 23% increase in conversion on our product listing page. Currently, I'm transitioning the product listing page to the cloud and refactoring the front end code into easily understandable functional units to get it under unit tests.

### Southern Company & Georgia Power // 2008 to present

I was the lead designer/developer for the Southern Company intranet serving 25,000 employees across Georgia, Mississippi, Florida, Alabama and Texas. I wrote all of the CSS and HTML for the basic theme and default properties of the components that make up the content management system. Currently, I lead a group of five in-house junior developers/designers. I also train end users at other operating companies throughout Southern Company.

#### Cleveland.com // 4/2006 - 12/2007

Cleveland.com is the online presence of The Plain Dealer, Cleveland, Ohio's, daily newspaper and The Sun News, a collection of Cleveland's community newspapers. Cleveland.com is a subsidiary of Advance Internet. While at Cleveland.com I cleaned up a lot of old, clunky code, redesigned pages with beautiful CSS, designed a hundred or so animated GIFs for advertisers, and performed any maintenance or troubleshooting as necessary.

#### **Sun News** // 2005 – 2006

The Sun News is a collection of community newspapers in Cleveland, OH. I worked as an illustrator creating creating maps and other graphic elements to accompany stories.

#### Cincinnati Citysearch // 2001

I was an Assistant Editor at CincinnatiCitysearch.com. At Citysearch I learned HTML. My duties included, writing stories, coding the stories, contributing photography, organizing campaigns, hiring and directing freelancers, editing story submissions, and working with local, regional and national editors.

# **Education**

Associate's Degree Visual Communication & Design, Cuyahoga Community College, 2006

BA English Literature & Journalism, University of Cincinnati, 2001